# Sondre Agledahl

Curriculum Vitae

Portfolio: sondre.io Email: sondre.agledahl.16@ucl.ac.uk Phone: (0)78 7376 1954

### Personal Summary

Games programmer, particularly experienced in Unity (2+ years), but with strong skills in low-level languages (C, C++ and assembly) as well. Currently pursuing a MEng Computer Science degree at University College London.

Dedicated past 3 years to developing independent games, with accolades including

- Unity game shortlisted as a finalist for the 2018 Rising Star game programming competition, which
  was the <u>highest-ranked game submission</u> in competition's second round.
- GameBoy Advance ROM hack, winner of "Best of 2016" award at a ROM Hacking website.
- Winning submission for the <u>2018 Escape Studios game jam</u> as sole programmer in team of five.

## Relevant work experience

July-Sept 2018	<ul> <li>Software engineering intern, Amazon (London, UK)</li> <li>Developed new internal REST service for creating and editing presentation themes for Alexa on the Echo Show device family.</li> <li>Created React-based web app for non-engineering designers to easily interact with service without programming knowledge.</li> </ul>
June 2017	<ul> <li>Freelance game programmer, Innotech LLC. (London, UK)</li> <li>Developed upon existing Unity-based match-three mobile puzzle game, single-handedly implementing many new features and game modes.</li> </ul>
June 2017-Present	<ul> <li>Microsoft Student Partner, Microsoft (London, UK)</li> <li>Wrote tutorials on game development topics (including Entity-Component System and Mixed Reality) for Microsoft Development Network.</li> <li>Lead organiser of PixelJam, Microsoft-sponsored game jam at UCL.</li> </ul>
Sept 2017-April 2018	<ul> <li>Computer Science lab mentor, University College London (London, UK)</li> <li>Tutored first-year computer science students in programming (C, Haskell, Java) every week.</li> </ul>

# **Education**

#### University College London (London, UK)

MEng Computer Science, September 2016 – present (Predicted 1st class)

- Game development director at UCL Tech Society: Organised and led <u>PixelJam</u>, university's first 24-hour game jam, with sponsorships from Microsoft, Unity and Studio Gobo
- Developed iOS AR game for visually impaired players in collaboration project with Microsoft
- Created space shooter game controlled by accelerometer on Arduino microcontroller in C
- Developed multi-platform medical application through C# / Xamarin for client at UCL Hospital

## Senja VGS (Finnsnes, Norway)

International Baccalaureate Diploma Programme, August 2014 – May 2016

- Received distinction for highest IB score ever awarded in Northern Norway (42)
- Founded and led programming tutoring group, teaching programming and game development through Python (with use of the PyGame framework)